# A. F. M. MINHAZUR RAHMAN

(+880)1710001958 | ☑ m.r.saurov@gmail.com | ☑ afm.minhazur@cse.ruet.ac.bd

⊕ mrsaurov.github.io | ⊕ cse.ruet.ac.bd/mrsaurov

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) graduate from Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology (RUET), Bangladesh, where I earned my Bachelor of Science degree with first-class honors (first position). Currently, I serve as an Assistant Professor at the same institution. My research focuses on deep learning, particularly in computer vision tasks such as segmentation and classification. I am passionate about contributing to advancements in computer vision, a field that I believe will significantly shape the future.

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Medical Image Analysis

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science** | *Computer Science and Engineering (CSE)*Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology (RUET)

Rajshahi, Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.89/4.00, Department Position: 1st

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) | Science 2015

Rajshahi College Rajshahi, Bangladesh

GPA: 5.00/5.00

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) | Science

Shiroil Govt. High School Rajshahi, Bangladesh

GPA: 5.00/5.00

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science & Engineering Lecturer, Department of Department of Computer Science & Engineering

Rajshahi, Bangladesh September 2024 – Present December 2021 – September 2024

2013

- Supervised 10 undergraduate students in their theses on deep learning, computer vision, and image analysis, providing guidance on research methodologies and project execution
- Courses taught: Algorithm Analysis & Design, Applied Statistics, Technical Writing & Presentation, Operating Systems, Parallel & Distributed Systems

# North Bengal International University

Lecturer

Rajshahi, Bangladesh March 2021 – December 2021

- Supervised undergraduate students in their software development projects
- Courses taught: Object Oriented Programming with Java, Computer Architecture & Organization

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

## **Published Book Chapters**

A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and Boshir Ahmed. "Hyperspectral Image Classification Using Factor Analysis and Convolutional Neural Networks." In Mohammad Shamsul Arefin, M. Shamim Kaiser, Anirban Bandyopadhyay, Md. Atiqur Rahman Ahad, and Kanad Ray, editors, Proceedings of the International Conference on Big Data, IoT, and Machine Learning, pages 129–139, Singapore, 2022. Springer Singapore.

# **Accepted Book Chapters**

• A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and Md. Ali Hossain. "Deep Learning Approach to Brain Tumor Segmentation from MRI Images." Accepted and presented at the International Conference on Big Data, IoT, and Machine Learning: BIM 2023. Currently under editing for publication in a Taylor & Francis book.

## **Published Conference Papers**

- A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and Md. Ali Hossain. "Attention-refined U-Net with Skip Connections for Effective Brain Tumor Segmentation from MRI images." In 2023 26th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT), pages 1–6, 2023.
- Kowshik Deb Nath, A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman, and Md. Ali Hossain. "An Attention-based Deep Learning Approach to Knee Injury Classification from MRI Images." In 2023 26th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT), pages 1–6, 2023.

# **Accepted Conference Papers**

 Noman Amin, Anwar Hossain Efat, A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and S. M. Mahedy Hasan. "Enhanced Skin Lesion Detection Using Concatenated DenseNet and Multi-Attention Mechanisms." Accepted for presentation at the 4th International Conference on Innovations in Science, Engineering and Technology (ICISET), 2024.

# RESEARCH PROJECTS

# Brain Tumor Segmentation Using Effective Deep Learning Approach

2022-23

Project Director

- A research project funded by the University Grants Commission (UGC), Bangladesh, and RUET.
- Research grant amount: 149,760 BDT
- Proposed a novel, efficient deep learning based model for semantic segmentation of brain tumors in MRI images

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

## Attendance Manager | Java

An Android application for taking class attendance, keeping track of students and generating attendance report.

Available on Github: Link

#### Med Organizer | Java

An Android application for keeping track of medication, setting reminders, keeping doctor appointment notes, etc.

Available on Github: Link

#### C-Like Compiler | C, Flex, Bison

Compiler for programming lanuguage similar to C that generates MIPS assembly code.

Available on Github: Link

## ACHIEVEMENTS

## Student of the Year - 4th Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 4th year with average 3.97 GPA and academic excellence.

## Student of the Year - 3rd Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 3rd year with average 3.93 GPA and academic excellence.

#### Student of the Year - 1st Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 1st year with average 3.94 GPA and academic excellence.

## Board Scholarship, Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

Awardee of the Rajshahi board scholarship in general grade

## **SKILLS**

- Machine Learning Libraries: TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch
- Programming Languages: Python (advanced), C++ (intermediate), Java (advanced)
- Version Control: Git
- Languages: Bangla (Native), English (Professional)

# REFERENCES

• Dr. Md. Ali Hossain

Professor

Department of Computer Science & Engineering Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology Email: ali.ruet@gmail.com,ali.hossain@cse.ruet.ac.bd

• Dr. Md. Al Mamun

Professor

Department of Computer Science & Engineering
Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology
Email: almamun00350@gmail.com,a.mamun@cse.ruet.ac.bd